Andrew Peirs // peirs.andrew@gmail.com // 07552239487

Senior React developer with 10 years of experience covering all aspects of frontend development. At Moodys, I architected greenfield projects, building out the frontend stack and coding an extensive component library. At ITV I worked on high-pressure, business-critical platforms that process over a billion pounds in sales a year. I have championed better coding practices, I have refactored and improved old code, I have mentored junior developers, and when it comes to pixel-perfect UI, I have super high standards.

EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Design at Course Careers // August 2024 - Present

I have recently completed a UI/UX design course where I learnt the design process from start to finish. How to perform user research and interviews, how to find key insights in the data gathered, how to create sketches and wireframes, and finally how to create high-fidelity designs using Figma. My goal is to become a developer who can produce amazing designs and high-quality functional code.

ITV // Senior Frontend Engineer February 2023 - August 2024

Worked with the Planet V team on a web platform to process advertising sales. Using TypeScript, React, Tailwind, GraphQL, and AWS, I touched on all aspects of frontend development.

- Helped to code and maintain an extensive component library built in Storybook using Typescript and Tailwind.
- Began to learn AWS by helping out with small backend tasks.
- Introduced architectural patterns like component composition to improve the developer experience and to ship features quicker.
- Ran the ITV frontend developer guild, where I helped educate developers on better coding practices, encouraged developers to give talks, and led healthy discussions on how we could improve our codebase.
- Led web accessibility improvements, ensuring our UI meets accessibility standards.
- Mentored junior developers and helped them to get comfortable and confident in their new role.

Travelling January 2022 - February 2023

Took a year off to travel and learn some new skills. I travelled extensively throughout Europe, meeting some great people and making friends from all over the world. This past year has made me a more well-rounded, confident, and balanced person.

Hive HR // Senior Web Developer September 2021 - January 2022

Lead a project to allow Hive users to generate an ad-hoc list of employees. This freed up Hive users from manually sending emails to each employee.

- Lead architect of the project with the aim of keeping the app as simple as possible.
- Maintained, built, and refactored React components for the HiveHR component library.
- Built an interactive, virtualised table from scratch that can display thousands of items.
- Extensively tested code and components using Cypress and React-Testing-Library.

Propa Code // React Dev Contractor September 2018 - September 2021

Frontend developer specialising in everything React, Typescript, Redux, GraphQL, and Cypress.

- Moodys // April 2021- August 2021
 - Architected and coded a complex financial dashboard to allow clients to gain better insights into their financial data.
- Delta Capita // September 2020 April 2021 As the lead developer, I planned, designed, architected, and coded a dynamic financial form generator. I took a block of JSON that represented a complex financial document and turned it into an online form. Giving users a centralised place to easily track and complete financial forms. The key features implemented are
 - Real-time collaboration using WebSockets that allows users to collaborate similar to Google Docs
 - A commenting system to ask internal Delta Capita employees for help and advice.
 - Designed app-wide state management using Redux and Redux-Toolkit.
 - Architected and coded a Delta Capita Component library allowing new applications to be built quicker.
 - Tested all code using Cypress and React-Testing-Library.
- Mazer LTD // April 2020 August 2020
 - Working under NDA on a medical-based application built with React Native.
- Equator // March 2020 May 2020
 - Used React to build complex user journey forms to navigate users along the dynamic paths of a financial investment application.
- RiskFirst // September 2018 March 2020 Architect of a suite of greenfield applications using React, Typescript, and Redux to allow users to visualise their financial data and gain better insights
 - Extensively used Redux to manage the state of data transformation pipelines in an interactive data transformation application.
 - Using HighCharts, I built custom bar, line, and area charts to create a financial dashboard that displays a user's massive financial dataset.
 - Built a custom SVG brush component to allow users to zoom in and out and have fine control over how they view their data.
 - Created and maintained deployment pipelines using Azure.
 - Used Cypress and React-Testing-Library to test the application and components.
 - Worked closely with lead developers in interviewing and hiring new developers.

Partnerize // React Developer September 2017 - August 2018

• Involved in building a custom component library to allow developers to easily rebrand the entire Partnerize application

Leighton // Web Developer December 2016 - September 2017

• Using Angular, I updated and rebranded features on the British Airways homepage.

The Floow // Android Developer October 2014 - August 2016

• Using Android and Java, I built telematic insurance apps to rate a driver's ability to

CrowdLab // Android Developer August 2013- October 2014

• Worked on the CrowdLab survey application using the Android SDK and Java.

EDUCATION

Derby University // BSc (Hons) Computer Games Programming 2009–2013

Key projects include building a graphics renderer in C++, using AI behaviour trees to make a Mexican standoff simulator, and building a generative music simulator.